[ grunts ]
[ panting ]
[ wings flapping ]
[ man ] Starling !
Starling .
Crawford wants to see you in his office .
[ Southern accent ] Thank you , sir .
[ gunfire ]
- [ buzzer sounds ] - [ gunfire continues ]
[ buzzer sounds ]
[ helicopter whirring ]
[ gunfire ]
- Clarice . - Hey .
Hey , I got right to the end .
[ buzzer sounds ]
[ elevator bell dings ]
[ men chattering ]
So there shouldn 't be any problem if you could –
- You looking for Crawford ? - Yes , sir .
He should be back in a couple minutes . Why don 't you wait in his office .
Okay .
Then I think they were over into Flushing .
Starling . Clarice M.
- Good morning . - Good morning , Mr. Crawford .
Sorry to pull you off the course on such short notice .
Your instructors tell me you 're doing well . Top quarter of your class .
I hope so . They haven 't posted any grades yet .
A job 's come up , and I thought about you .
Not a job really . More of an interesting errand .
- Sit down . - Yes , sir .
- I remember you from my seminar at UVA . - Yeah .
You grilled me pretty hard , as I recall ,
on the Bureau 's civil rights record in the Hoover years .
- I gave you an " A. " - A-minus , sir .
Let 's see . Double major – psych and criminology .
Graduated magna . Summer internships at the Reitzinger Clinic .
It says here , when you graduate ,
you wanna come to work for me in behavioral science .
Yes . Very much , sir . Very much .
We 're interviewing all the serial killers now in custody
for a psycho-behavioral profile .
Could be a real help in unsolved cases .
Most of them have been happy to talk to us .
You spook easily , Starling ?
Not yet , sir .
See , the one we want most refuses to cooperate .
I want you to go after him again today in the asylum .
Who 's the subject ?
The psychiatrist , Hannibal Lecter .
" Hannibal the Cannibal . "
I don 't expect him to talk to you ...
but I have to be able to say we tried .
So , if he won 't cooperate , I want just straight reporting –
how 's he look , how 's his cell look .
Is he sketching , drawing ? If he is , what 's he sketching ?
Here 's a , uh , dossier on Lecter ...
copy of our questionnaire , and a special ID for you .
Have your memo on my desk by 0800 Wednesday .
Okay .
Um , excuse me , sir , but why the urgency ?
Lecter 's been in prison for so many years now .
Is there some connection between him and Buffalo Bill maybe ?
I wish there were .
I want your full attention , Starling .
Yes , sir .
Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter .
Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over all the physical procedures used with him .
Do not deviate from them for any reason whatsoever .
And you 're to tell him nothing personal , Starling .
Believe me , you don 't want Hannibal Lecter inside your head .
Just do your job , but never forget what he is .
And what is that ?
[ man ] Oh , he 's a monster .
Pure psychopath .
So rare to capture one alive .
From a research point of view , Lecter is our most prized asset .
Well .
You know , we get a lot of detectives here , but , I must say ,
I can 't ever remember one as attractive .
Will you be in Baltimore overnight ?
Because this can be quite a fun town if you have the right guide .
[ chuckles ] I 'm sure this is a great town , Dr. Chilton ,
but , um , my instructions are to talk to Dr. Lecter and report back this afternoon .
I see . Well , let 's make this quick then .
We 've tried to study him , of course ,
but he 's much too sophisticated for the standard tests .
And , oh , my , does he hate us . [ chuckling ]
He thinks I 'm his nemesis .
Crawford 's very clever , isn 't he , using you ?
- What do you mean , sir ? - Pretty , young woman to turn him on .
I don 't believe Lecter 's even seen a woman in eight years .
And , oh , are you ever his taste , so to speak .
I graduated from UVA , Doctor . It is not a charm school .
Good . Then you should be able to remember the rules .
[ man shouting ]
Do not touch the glass . Do not approach the glass .
You pass him nothing but soft paper . No pencils or pens .
No staples or paper clips in his paper .
Use the sliding food carrier . No exceptions .
If he attempts to pass you anything , do not accept it .
- Do you understand me ? - Yes , I understand , sir .
I 'm going to show you why we insist on such precautions .
On the afternoon of July 8 , 1981 ,
he complained of chest pains and was taken to the dispensary .
His mouthpiece and restraints were removed for an EKG .
When the nurse leaned over him , he did this to her .
The doctors managed to reset her jaw , more or less , save one of her eyes .
His pulse never got above 85 ,
even when he ate her tongue .
- I keep him in here . - Dr . Chilton .
[ buzzer sounds ]
Um , if Lecter feels that you 're his enemy ,
then , um , well , maybe we 'll have more luck if I go in by myself .
What do you think ?
[ monitor beeping ]
You might have suggested this in my office and saved me the time .
Yes , sir , but then I – I would have missed the pleasure of your company , sir .
When she 's finished , bring her out .
- [ radio chatter ] - [ printer clattering ]
Hi . I 'm Barney .
He told you don 't get near the glass ?
- Yes , he did . Clarice Starling . - Mm-hmm .
Nice to meet you , Clarice . You can hang your coat up here if you like .
Oh , thank you . I will .
He 's past the others – the last cell .
You keep to the right .
[ slams , lock turns ]
- I put out a chair for you . - Oh , yes . That 's very good . Thank you .
I 'll be watching . You 'll do fine .
[ man ] Hi .
[ hissing ] I can smell your cunt !
- Good morning . - Dr . Lecter , my name is Clarice Starling .
May I speak with you ?
You 're one of Jack Crawford 's , aren 't you ?
I am , yes .
May I see your credentials ?
Certainly .
Closer , please .
Closer .
That expires in one week . You 're not real FBI , are you ?
I 'm still in training at the academy .
Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me ?
Yes . I 'm a student . I 'm here to learn from you .
Maybe you can decide for yourself whether or not I 'm qualified enough to do that .
Mmm .
That is rather slippery of you , Agent Starling .
Sit . Please .
Now then , tell me , what did Miggs say to you ?
Multiple Miggs in the next cell .
He hissed at you . What did he say ?
He said , " I can smell your cunt . "
I see .
I myself cannot .
[ inhales , sniffing ]
[ gasps ]
You use Evyan skin cream .
And sometimes you wear L 'Air du Temps .
But not today .
Did you do all these drawings , Doctor ?
Ah .
That is the Duomo seen from the Belvedere .
Do you know Florence ?
All that detail just from memory , sir ?
Memory , Agent Starling , is what I have instead of a view .
Well , perhaps you 'd care to lend us your view on this questionnaire , sir .
Oh , no , no , no , no .
You were doing fine .
You had been courteous and receptive to courtesy .
You had established trust with the ... embarrassing truth about Miggs .
And now this ... ham-handed segue into your questionnaire .
[ clicking tongue ]
It won 't do .
I 'm only asking you to look at this , Doctor .
Either you will or you won 't .
Yeah . Jack Crawford must be very busy indeed
if he is recruiting help from the student body .
Busy hunting that new one , Buffalo Bill .
What a naughty boy he is .
Do you know why he 's called " Buffalo Bill " ?
Please tell me . The newspapers won 't say .
Well , it started as a bad joke in Kansas City Homicide .
They said , " This one likes to skin his humps . "
Why do you think he removes their skins ,
Agent Starling ?
Thrill me with your acumen .
It excites him .
Most serial killers keep some sort of trophies from their victims .
- I didn 't . - No .
No , you ate yours .
You send that through now .
[ tray slides open , closes ]
Hmm .
[ affecting Southern accent ] Oh , Agent Starling .
You think you can dissect me with this blunt little tool ?
No . I – I thought that your knowledge –
You 're so ambitious , aren 't you ?
You know what you look like to me with your good bag and your cheap shoes ?
You look like a rube –
a well-scrubbed , hustling rube with a little taste .
Good nutrition 's given you some length of bone ,
but you 're not more than one generation from poor white trash ,
are you , Agent Starling ?
And that accent you 've tried so desperately to shed – pure West Virginia .
What does your father do ? Is he a coal miner ?
Does he stink of the lamp ?
And , oh , how quickly the boys found you –
all those tedious , sticky fumblings in the back seats of cars
while you could only dream of getting out , getting anywhere ,
getting all the way to the FBI .
You see a lot , Doctor .
But are you strong enough to point
that high-powered perception at yourself ?
What about it ? Why don 't you – Why don 't you look at yourself
and write down what you see ?
Or maybe you 're afraid to .
[ tray slams ]
A census taker once tried to test me .
I ate his liver with some fava beans
and a nice Chianti .
[ sucking teeth ]
You fly back to school now , little Starling .
Fly , fly , fly .
[ whispering ] Fly , fly , fly .
[ man moaning ]
[ moaning loudly ]
I bit my wrist so I could die .
[ laughing ] Look at the blood !
- [ Gasps ] - Gotcha ! [ laughing ]
Miggs ! You stupid fuck !
[ laughing ]
I 'm gonna kill him !
Agent Starling ! Come back ! Agent Starling ! Agent Starling !
I would not have had that happen to you . Discourtesy is unspeakably ugly to me .
- Then do this test for me . - No . But I will make you happy .
I 'll give you a chance for what you love most .
- And what is that , Doc – - Advancement , of course . Listen carefully .
Look deep within yourself , Clarice Starling .
Go seek out Miss Mofet , an old patient of mine – M-O-F-E-T .
Go . I don 't think Miggs could manage again quite so soon , even though he is crazy .
- Go now ! - [ men shouting ]
[ door closes ]
[ gasps ]
- Hi , Bill . - [ car door closes ]
- Hey ! - Daddy !
Hey , Clarice .
Hello , my girl .
- Did you get any bad guys today , Daddy ? - No , angel . They all got away today .
Aw , shoot .
- [ dog barks ] - [ Clarice sobbing ]
FBI ! Hands up !
- Don 't move ! - Turn around .
Hands behind your back . Thumbs up .
[ handcuffs clicking ]
- [ gun clicks ] - You 're dead , Starling .
- [ buzzer sounds ] - Johnson , good job .
Good entry . Good commands .
- Starling , where 's your danger area ? - In the corner , sir .
- Did you check the corner ? - No , sir .
That 's the reason you 're dead .
3-109 .
3-109 . Breaking doors or windows
to enter or exit .
Uh , Rule 4-048 .
[ machine clicks ]
Clarice . Phone . It 's the guru .
- Crawford ? - Yeah .
Thanks , Ardelia .
- Starling ? - Sir .
Miggs is dead .
Dead ?
How ?
The orderly heard Lecter whispering to him all afternoon and Miggs crying .
They found him at bed check . He 'd swallowed his own tongue .
Starling ?
Yeah . I 'm – I 'm still here , sir .
I just – I don 't know how to feel about this .
You don 't have to feel any way about it . Lecter did it to amuse himself .
Look , I know it got ugly today , but –
He mentioned a name at the end – a Mofet .
Any follow-up on her ?
Uh , well , Lecter altered or destroyed most of his patients ' histories prior to capture ,
so there 's no record of anyone named Mofet .
But , um , I thought the " yourself " reference was , uh , too hokey for Lecter .
So I figured , he 's from Baltimore ,
and I looked in the phone book , and there 's a Your Self Storage facility
right outside of downtown Baltimore , sir .
[ man ] Unit 31 was leased for 10 years ,
prepaid in full .
The contract was in the name
of a ... Miss Hester Mofet .
So nobody 's been in here since 1980 ?
Not to my knowledge .
Privacy is a great concern to my customers .
[ grunts ] Yes . I won 't disturb anything . I promise .
I 'll be outta here before you know it .
- [ door clanking ] - Can I help you ?
Yes , actually . I can 't –
It 's stuck .
You could return tomorrow with my son .
- What about him ? - [ chuckles ]
I would ask my driver to help you ,
but he detests physical labor .
Right .
Well , you just stay here . I 'll be back in one minute .
[ door creaking ]
[ grunting ]
- [ door creaking ] - Stuck .
- Hand me that flashlight , sir . - [ tire iron clatters ]
Oh .
Um , if this door should fall down or –
[ forced laugh ] anything else ,
uh , this is the number for our Baltimore field office .
Now , they know that you 're with me . You call them if anything should happen .
Yes , Miss Starling .
- [ fabric rips ] - Ow !
[ door closes ]
Clarice , I cleared the way for you .
- Watch yourself . - Okay . Thanks .
" Hester Mofet . " It 's an anagram , isn 't it , Doctor ?
" Hester Mofet . " " The rest of me . "
" Miss the Rest of Me . " Meaning that you rented that garage ?
Thank you .
Your bleeding has stopped .
[ TV : no audible dialogue ]
How did you –
It 's nothing .
It 's just a scratch .
Dr. Lecter , whose head is in that bottle ?
Why don 't you ask me about Buffalo Bill ?
Why , do you know something about him ?
I might if I saw the case file . You could get that for me .
Why don 't we talk about Miss Mofet ? You wanted me to find him .
His real name is Benjamin Raspail .
A former patient of mine whose romantic attachments ran
to , shall we say , the exotic .
I did not kill him , I assure you .
Merely tucked him away very much as I found him
after he 'd missed three appointments .
But ... if you didn 't kill him , then who did , sir ?
Who can say ? Best thing for him really .
His therapy was going nowhere .
His dress , uh , makeup –
Raspail was a transvestite ?
In life ? Oh , no .
Garden-variety manic-depressive .
Tedious . Very tedious .
No , no . Just think of him as a kind of experiment ,
a fledgling killer 's first effort at transformation .
How did you feel when you saw him , Clarice ?
Scared at first , then ... exhilarated .
Jack Crawford is helping your career , isn 't he ?
Apparently he likes you , and you like him too .
I never thought about it .
Do you think Jack Crawford wants you sexually ?
True , he is much older ,
but do you think he visualizes scenarios , exchanges , fucking you ?
[ scoffs ]
That doesn 't interest me , Doctor .
And frankly , it 's – it 's the sort of thing that Miggs would say .
Not anymore .
[ clanging ]
Thank you , Barney .
What happened to your drawings ?
Punishment , you see . For Miggs .
Just like that gospel program .
When you leave , they 'll turn the volume way up .
Dr. Chilton does enjoy his petty torments .
What did you mean by " transformation , " Doctor ?
I 've been in this room for eight years now , Clarice ...
and I know they will never , ever let me out while I 'm alive .
What I want is a view .
I want a window where I can see a tree or even water .
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton .
What did you mean by " fledgling killer " ?
Are you saying that he 's killed again ?
I 'm offering you a psychological profile on Buffalo Bill
based on the case evidence .
I 'll help you catch him , Clarice .
You know who he is , don 't you ?
Tell me who decapitated your patient , Doctor .
All good things to those who wait .
I 've waited , Clarice .
But how long can you and ol ' Jackie boy wait ?
Our little Billy must already be searching for that next special lady .
[ radio : man singing ] ♪ After all it was a great big world ♪
♪ With lots of places To run to ♪
[ singing along ] ♪ Yeah , and if she had to die tryin ' ♪
♪ She had that one little promise She was gonna keep ♪
♪ Oh , yes , all right ♪
♪ Take it easy , baby ♪
♪ Make it last all night ♪
♪ She was an American girl ♪
[ whirring ]
[ radio : song continues , faint ]
[ engine stops ]
[ cat meowing ]
Hey , little cheeper .
I 'll be right there .
[ panting ]
[ grunts ] Goddamn .
Fuckin ' – Geez .
[ chair scraping ]
Can I help you with that ?
- Would you ? - Sure .
- Thank you . - That 's all right .
- You look kinda handicapped . - Yeah .
I got it this far . I just can 't get it up in the truck .
I could use all the help I can get . Just grab that .
- Up . - [ grunts ] Okay .
Yeah . Just set it down . That 's good .
Uh , get in the truck , and I wanna push it all the way up .
- I really appreciate this . Thank you . - All right . Yeah .
Thank you . Now – Push it all the way back .
Okay . Is this good ?
- Yeah , that 's good . That 's great . - Ah –
- That 's great . - Okay .
- Hey , say , are you about a size 14 ? - Sorry ?
- [ screams , groaning ] - [ blows landing ]
[ groaning ]
Good .
[ whimpering faintly ]
Oh , good .
Good .
[ engine starts ]
[ growls quietly ]
- [ blows landing ] - [ man ] Hold !
[ man shouts ]
- [ whistle blows ] - [ man ] Starling !
Outside . Let 's go .
[ man 2 ] Cindy ! In the ring for Starling ! Let 's go !
[ whistle blows ]
[ sirens wailing ]
- FBI ! Hold it ! - Hold it right there !
Saddle up . Pack your field gear . You 're movin ' out . You 're goin ' with Crawford .
- Where ? - They found a girl 's body down in West Virginia .
Been in the water about a week . Looks like a Buffalo Bill-type situation .
[ Crawford ] Keeps ' em alive for three days . We don 't know why .
There 's no evidence of rape or physical abuse prior to death .
All the mutilation you see there is postmortem .
Okay . Three days .
Then he shoots them , skins them , and dumps them –
each body in a different river .
The water leaves us no trace evidence of any kind .
That 's Frederica Bimmel , the first one .
Her body was the only one he took the trouble to weight down ,
so actually she was the third girl found .
After her , he got lazy .
Okay . Let 's see .
Circles where the girls were abducted .
Arrows where their bodies were found .
This new one today washed up here .
Elk River , West Virginia .
[ men chattering ]
Look at ' em , Starling . Tell me what you see .
Well , he 's a white male .
Uh , serial killers tend to hunt within their own ethnic groups .
Um , he 's not a drifter .
He 's got his own ... house somewhere , not an apartment .
- Why ? - What he does with them takes privacy .
He 's in his 30s or 40s .
He 's got real physical strength , combined with an older man 's self-control .
He 's-He 's cautious , precise .
And he 's never impulsive . He 'll never stop .
Why not ?
He 's got a real taste for it now , and he 's getting better at his work .
Not bad , Starling . Questions ?
Yes , sir . Um , you haven 't mentioned anything about the information contained in my report
or Dr. Lecter 's offer , sir .
I 'm considering it .
That 's why you sent me in there , isn 't it ?
To get his help on Buffalo Bill , sir ?
Well , if that was the case , then I just –
I just wish I was in on it , that 's all .
If I 'd sent you in there with an actual agenda ,
Lecter would have known it instantly .
He would have toyed with you , then turned to stone .
[ bell tolling ]
Excuse me , Sheriff Perkins . These are the FBI people .
Sheriff Perkins . Jack Crawford , FBI .
Special Agent Terry , Agent Starling .
We appreciate being invited to your jurisdiction .
I didn 't call you . That was somebody from the state attorney 's office .
We 'll extend you every courtesy , but right now I –
Sheriff .
[ whispering ] This type of sex crime has certain aspects
I 'd just as soon discuss in private .
Know what I mean ?
- [ door opens ] - [ organ : " Rock of Ages " ]
[ briefcase clatters ]
- [ door opens ] - [ Sheriff ] Oscar .
- Fetch Dr. Akin from the chapel . - [ man ] Yes , sir .
Starling , we 're back here .
Tell Lamar to come on when he 's finished playing his music .
- Yeah , we 'll be sending in a minute . - [ chattering ]
[ beeping ]
- I need a – I need a six-way link-up . - [ chattering loudly ]
Chicago , Detroit – What ? What ?
Uh , excuse me .
[ clears throat ] Excuse me , gentlemen .
You officers and gentlemen , listen here now . There 's things we need to do for her .
I know that you all brought her this far
and that her folks would thank you if they could
for your – for your kindness and your sensitivity .
But now , please , go on now and let us take care of her .
Go on now .
- Thank you . - [ police radio chatter ]
Thank you .
[ Crawford ] Okay , good .
Yeah , that 's right . West Vir – Yeah . Elk River .
Stand by for transmission .
[ machine beeps ]
Ray .
[ Crawford ] Doctor , Lamar , let 's take a look at her .
- [ whispers ] Jesus . - [ sighs ]
Okay , Starling .
Bill .
Star-shaped contact entrance wound
over the , uh , sternum .
Um , muzzle stamp at the top .
- [ Akin ] Wrongful death . - Wrongful death .
[ camera shutter clicks , whirs ]
[ Akin ] She 'll have to go to the state pathologist at Claxton .
Well , I-I 'd better get back to that service . Lamar 'll help ya .
- Lord Almighty . - [ shutter clicks , whirs ]
[ shutter continues clicking ]
[ Crawford ] What else do you see , Starling ?
Well , she 's not local .
Her ears are pierced three times , and there 's , uh –
Uh , glitter nail polish . It looks like town to me .
Two of her fingernails are broken off , and there 's , uh –
there 's dirt or grit under them .
It looks like she 's tried to claw her way through something .
[ clicks , whirs ]
[ Crawford ] Ray , get pictures of her teeth . We 'll fax them to Missing Persons .
Right .
[ Terry ] Let 's do another .
[ clicks , whirs ]
She 's got something in her throat .
When a body comes out of the water ,
lots of times there 's , like , leaves and things in the mouth .
[ air hissing ]
What is that , some kind of seed pod ?
No , sir . That 's a bug cocoon .
But there 's no way that could get way down in there like that .
Not unless somebody shoved it in there .
She 'll be easier to print when we turn her over .
- Lamar , will you give me a hand with this ? - Yes , sir , I will .
Ooh , Jack .
- What do you make of these ? - Hmm .
Different configuration than the other victims . Get close-ups .
[ Clarice ] The victim 's skin removed at this time
in two large diamond-shaped sections above the buttocks .
Stellate exit wound level with the second or the third thoracic vertebrae ,
approximately six inches from the right shoulder blade .
[ Crawford ] Starling .
When – When I told that sheriff we shouldn 't talk in front of a woman ,
that really burned you , didn 't it ?
It was just smoke , Starling . I had to get rid of him .
It matters , Mr. Crawford . Cops look at you to see how to act .
- It matters . - Point taken .
Ligature marks found around the wrists ,
not around the ankles .
This would indicate that the skinning was postmortem .
[ elevator bell dings ]
- [ man ] Time , Pilch . My move . - [ Pilch ] No fair . You lured him with produce .
Tough noogies . Still my turn .
[ blows ]
Nice and slow , baby .
If the beetle moves one of your men , does that still count ?
Of course it counts . How do you play ?
Agent Starling ?
[ man 1 ] Where the heck did this come from ?
It 's practically mush .
It was found behind the soft palate of a murder victim .
The body was in the Elk River in West Virginia .
- It 's Buffalo Bill , isn 't it ? - I 'm afraid I can 't tell you any more about that .
We heard about it on the radio .
You mean this is , like , a clue from a real murder case ?
- Cool ! - Just ignore him . He 's not a PhD .
A Sphingid ceratomia maybe .
Boy , he 's a big sucker .
Okay . Let 's check morphology .
Uh-huh . Uh-huh .
What do you do when you 're not detecting , Agent Starling ?
[ chuckles ] Try to be a student , Dr. Pilcher .
You ever go out for cheeseburgers and beer ?
The amusing house wine ?
Are you hitting on me , Doctor ?
- Yes . - Gotcha .
- What do you got , Roden ? - Agent Starling .
Meet Mr. Acherontia styx .
Weird .
Better known to his friends as the death 's-head moth .
- And where does it come from ? - That 's what 's strange .
- They only live in Asia . - Asia ?
In this country , they 'd have to be specially raised from imported eggs .
Uh , somebody grew this guy . Fed him honey and nightshade .
Kept him warm .
Somebody loved him .
[ rock music playing , faint ]
[ woman , faint ] Please .
Hello ?
[ rock continues ]
[ woman ] Where are you ?
Let me out of here !
[ singing along softly ]
- Hey ! - [ dog barking ]
- Please help me ! - [ dog continues barking ]
Someone help me ! Please !
Why won 't you answer me ? Please !
[ TV : program theme ]
- Good morning . I 'm Donna Ferucci . - I 'm Gene Cassel with sports .
And I 'm Tim Langhorn . Our top story for this morning .
Catherine Martin , the 25-year-old daughter of Senator Ruth Martin ,
listed first as a missing person ,
is now believed to have been kidnapped by the serial killer known only as Buffalo Bill .
Memphis police sources indicate that the missing girl 's blouse –
- Thank you . - has been identified – sliced up the back –
in what has become a kind of grim , all-too-familiar calling card .
Young Catherine Martin , as we 've said , is the only daughter
of US Senator Ruth Martin , the Republican junior senator from Tennessee .
And while her kidnapping is not at this point considered to be politically motivated ,
nevertheless , it has stirred the government to its highest levels .
Reached for comment on the ski slopes of Stowe , Vermont ,
the president himself said to be , and I quote , " intensely concerned . "
- Just moments ago , Senator Martin – - Excuse me .
taped this dramatic personal plea .
[ Senator Martin ] I 'm speaking now to the person who 's holdin ' my daughter .
Catherine is very gentle and kind .
Talk to her and you 'll see .
You have the power .
You are in charge .
I know you can feel love and compassion .
You have a wonderful chance to show the whole world
that you can be merciful as well as strong ,
that you 're big enough to treat Catherine
better than the world has treated you .
You have that power .
Please .
My daughter is Catherine .
- [ Ardelia ] Boy , that 's smart . - Release her unharmed .
- Jesus , that 's really smart . - [ man ] She keeps repeating the name .
If he sees Catherine as a person and not just an object ,
it 's harder to tear her up .
Please , release my little girl .
[ sirens wailing ]
What you 're doing , Miss Starling , is coming into my hospital
to conduct an interview and refusing to share information with me for the third time .
Sir , I told you this is just a routine follow-up on the Raspail case .
- He is my patient . I have rights . - I understand that , sir .
Look , I am not just some turnkey , Miss Starling .
This is the number for the US Attorney 's office .
Please , either you discuss this with him or you let me do my job .
Do you understand ?
If your profile helps us catch Buffalo Bill
in time to save Catherine Martin ...
the senator promises you a transfer
to the VA hospital at Oneida Park , New York , with a view of the woods nearby .
Maximum security still applies , of course .
You 'd have reasonable access to books .
Best of all though ,
one week of the year ,
you get to leave the hospital
and go here .
Plum Island .
Every day of that week , you may walk on the beach ,
you may swim in the ocean – for up to one hour –
under SWAT team surveillance , of course .
- [ exhales ] - And there you have it .
A copy of the Buffalo Bill case file .
Copy of the senator 's offer .
This offer is non-negotiable and final .
Catherine Martin dies , you get nothing .
[ tray clangs ]
" Plum Island Animal Disease Research Center . "
Sounds charming .
That 's only part of the island . There 's a very – very nice beach .
Terns nest there . There 's beautiful –
Terns ? Mm .
If I help you , Clarice , it will be " turns " with us too .
Quid pro quo . I tell you things , you tell me things .
Not about this case though . About yourself .
Quid pro quo . Yes or no ?
Yes or no , Clarice ? Poor little Catherine is waiting .
Go , Doctor .
What is your worst memory of childhood ?
Death of my father .
Tell me about it . And don 't lie , or I 'll know .
He was the town marshal , and ...
one night he
surprised two burglars coming out of the back of a drugstore .
They shot him .
Was he killed outright ?
No . He was very strong . He lasted more than a month .
My mother died when I was very young , so –
[ exhales ]
My father had become the whole world to me ,
and , uh , when he left me , I had nothing .
I was 10 years old .
You 're very frank , Clarice .
I think it would be quite something to know you in private life .
Quid pro quo , Doctor .
So tell me about Miss West Virginia . Was she a large girl ?
- Yes . - Big through the hips ?
- Roomy ? - They all were .
What else ?
She had an object deliberately inserted into her throat .
Now , that hasn 't been made public yet . We don 't know what it means .
Was it a butterfly ?
Yes . A moth .
Just like the one we found in Benjamin Raspail 's head an hour ago .
Why does he place them there , Doctor ?
The significance of the moth is change .
Caterpillar into chrysalis or pupa ...
and , from thence , into beauty .
Our Billy wants to change too .
There 's no correlation in the literature between transsexualism and violence .
- Transsexuals are very passive . - Clever girl .
You 're so close to the way you 're gonna catch him . Do you realize that ?
No . Tell me why .
After your father 's murder , you were orphaned .
What happened next ?
I don 't imagine the answer is on those second-rate shoes , Clarice .
I went to live with my mother 's cousin and her husband in Montana .
They had a ranch .
Was it a cattle ranch ?
Sheep and horses .
How long did you live there ?
Two months .
Why so briefly ?
I ran away .
Why , Clarice ?
Did the rancher make you perform fellatio ?
Did he sodomize you ?
No . He was a very decent man .
Quid pro quo , Doctor .
Billy is not a real transsexual .
But he thinks he is . He tries to be .
He 's tried to be a lot of things , I expect .
You said I was very close to the way we would catch him .
What did you mean , Doctor ?
There are three major centers for transsexual surgery –
Johns Hopkins , the University of Minnesota , and Columbus Medical Center .
I wouldn 't be surprised if Billy had applied for sex reassignment
at one or all of them
and been rejected .
On what basis would they reject him ?
[ Lecter 's voice ] Look for severe childhood disturbances
associated with violence .
Our Billy wasn 't born a criminal , Clarice .
He was made one through years of systematic abuse .
Billy hates his own identity , you see ,
and he thinks that makes him a transsexual .
But his pathology is a thousand times more savage
and more terrifying .
[ dog growls ]
It rubs lotion on its skin . It does this whenever it 's told .
[ gasping ] Mister , my family will pay cash .
Whatever ransom you 're askin ' for , they 'll pay it .
It rubs the lotion on its skin , or else it gets the hose again .
[ barks ]
Yes , it will , Precious . It will get the hose .
[ whimpering ] Okay . Okay . Okay .
Okay . Okay .
Okay .
Mister , if you let me go , I won 't – I won 't press charges .
I promise .
See , my mom is a real important woman .
I guess you already know that .
Now it places the lotion in the basket .
[ sobbing ] Please ! Please ! I want to go home .
I want to go home , please !
Please .
It places the lotion in the basket .
I want to see my mommy ! Please –
I want to see my – I want – [ sobbing ]
I want – I want to see – [ mouths words ]
- Put the fucking lotion in the basket ! - [ Precious barking ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
[ screaming continues ]
[ mock screaming ]
You still think you 're gonna walk on some beach and see the birdies ?
[ chuckles ] No , I don 't think so .
I called Senator Ruth Martin .
She never heard of any deal with you .
[ chuckling ] They scammed you , Hannibal .
Stand outside .
And shut the door .
- Barney . - Mm-hmm .
[ door closing ]
There never was a deal with Senator Martin , but there is now .
I designed it .
Of course , I worked in a few conditions for my own benefit as well .
Identify Buffalo Bill by name , and if the girl is found in time ,
Senator Martin will have you transferred
to Brushy Mountain State Prison in Tennessee .
Answer me , Hannibal .
You answer me now , or by God , you 'll never leave this cell .
Who is Buffalo Bill ?
His first name is Louis .
I 'll tell the rest to the senator herself , but only in Tennessee .
And I have a few conditions of my own .
Clean him up and get him ready to go .
[ man over phone ] Jack , Hannibal Lecter 's being transferred to Memphis .
Transferred ?
Did you have a trainee make some sort of phony offer to Lecter in the senator 's name ?
Yeah . I rolled the dice . I had to .
Well , she 's mad as hell , Jack . Paul Krendler 's over here from Justice .
She 's asking him to take over in Memphis .
[ sirens wailing ]
Welcome to Memphis , Dr. Lecter .
I 'm Lieutenant Boyle . This is Sergeant Patrick .
Now , we 're gonna treat you as good as you treat us .
You be a gentleman , you 're gonna get three hots and a cot .
Sir , if you 'll sign right here , we 'll have us a legal transfer .
Where is it ?
Here , sir . Use mine .
[ exhaling ]
Senator Martin , Dr. Hannibal Lecter .
Dr. Lecter .
I brought an affidavit guaranteeing your new rights .
You 'll want to read it before I sign .
I won 't waste your time or Catherine 's time bargaining for petty privileges .
Clarice Starling and that awful Jack Crawford
have wasted far too much time already .
I only pray they haven 't doomed the poor girl .
Let me help you now , and I will trust you when it is all over .
You have my word . Paul ?
Buffalo Bill 's real name is Louis Friend .
I met him just once .
He was referred to me in April or May 1980 by my patient Benjamin Raspail .
They were lovers , you see .
But Raspail had become very frightened .
Apparently , Louis had murdered a transient
and done things with the skin .
We need his address and a physical description .
Tell me , Senator ,
did you nurse Catherine yourself ?
- What ? - Did you breast-feed her ?
- Wait a minute . - Yes , I did .
- Toughened your nipples , didn 't it ? - You son of a bitch !
[ Lecter ] Amputate a man 's leg , and he can still feel it tickling .
Tell me , Mom , when your little girl is on the slab , where will it tickle you ?
Take this thing back to Baltimore .
Five-foot-ten , strongly built , about 180 pounds .
Hair blond , eyes pale blue . He 'd be about 35 now .
He said he lived in Philadelphia but may have lied .
That 's all I can remember , Mom .
But if I think of any more , I will let you know .
Oh , and , Senator , just one more thing .
Love your suit .
[ Chilton ] I can tell you now that in a meeting earlier this evening
with Senator Ruth Martin , Dr. Lecter agreed to assist in the investigation
of trying to find the abductor of Catherine Martin , Buffalo Bill .
- How do you fit in , sir ? - It 's through my unique insight
into Lecter 's mind that this breakthrough was possible .
And Buffalo Bill 's real name ?
Buffalo Bill 's real name is now a matter of record with the proper authorities .
- Can you give us more information ? - My name is Dr. Frederick Chilton .
- How do you spell that ? - That 's C-H –
Are you with Dr. Chilton 's group ?
Uh , well , I just saw him outside , sir .
Access to Lecter is strictly limited . We 've been getting death threats .
I understand , sir .
Log in and check your weapon .
[ Krendler ] I can 't take all the credit for myself .
Senator Martin , the Justice Department ,
people at the FBI , the folks at the Baltimore State Hospital .
And now for the hard part , apprehending the suspect .
- Excuse me , folks . I have to catch a flight . - [ reporters clamoring ]
[ phone rings ]
Command desk . Officer Jacobs .
- [ officer ] Is it true what they 're saying ? - Huh ?
He 's some kind of vampire .
- They don 't have a name for what he is . - [ elevator bell dings ]
You do know the rules , ma 'am ?
Yes , Lieutenant Boyle . I 've questioned him before .
Go ahead .
Good evening , Clarice .
I thought you might like your drawings back , Doctor .
Just until you get your view .
How very thoughtful .
Or did Jack Crawford send you for one last wheedle
before you 're both booted off the case ?
No , I came because I wanted to .
People will say we 're in love .
Tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk , tsk .
Anthrax Island .
That was an especially nice touch , Clarice .
Yours ?
Yes .
Yeah .
That was good .
Pity about poor Catherine though . Ticktock , ticktock , ticktock , ticktock .
Your anagrams are showing , Doctor .
Louis Friend ? [ scoffs ]
Iron sulfide , also known as fool 's gold .
Oh , Clarice , your problem is you need to get more fun out of life .
You were telling me the truth back in Baltimore , sir .
Please continue now .
I 've read the case files . Have you ?
Everything you need to find him is right there in those pages .
- Then tell me how . - First principles , Clarice .
Simplicity .
Read Marcus Aurelius .
Of each particular thing , ask , what is it in itself ?
What is its nature ?
What does he do , this man you seek ?
He kills women .
No . That is incidental .
What is the first and principal thing he does ?
What needs does he serve by killing ?
Anger .
Um ... social acceptance and , um , sexual frustration , sir .
No . He covets .
That is his nature .
And how do we begin to covet , Clarice ?
Do we seek out things to covet ?
Make an effort to answer now .
No . We just –
No . We begin by coveting what we see every day .
Don 't you feel eyes moving over your body , Clarice ?
And don 't your eyes seek out the things you want ?
All right , yes . Now please tell me how .
No .
It is your turn to tell me , Clarice . You don 't have any more vacations to sell .
Why did you leave that ranch ?
Doctor , we don 't have any more time for any of this now .
But we don 't reckon time the same way , do we , Clarice ?
This is all the time you 'll ever have .
Later . Now , please , listen to me . We 've only got five –
No ! I will listen now .
After your father 's murder , you were orphaned . You were 10 years old .
You went to live with cousins on a sheep and horse ranch in Montana .
And ?
And one morning , I just ran away .
Not " just , " Clarice . What set you off ?
You started at what time ?
Early . Still dark .
Then something woke you , didn 't it ? Was it a dream ?
What was it ?
I heard a strange noise .
It was ...
screaming .
Some kind of screaming , like a child 's voice .
What did you do ?
I went downstairs , outside .
I crept up into the barn house .
I was so scared to look inside , but I had to .
What did you see , Clarice ?
What did you see ?
Lambs .
They were screaming . [ inhales ]
They were slaughtering the spring lambs ?
And they were screaming .
And you ran away ?
No .
First I tried to free them . I –
I opened the gate to their pen , but they wouldn 't run .
They just stood there , confused . They wouldn 't run .
But you could , and you did , didn 't you ?
Yes .
I took one lamb and I ran away as fast as I could .
Where were you going , Clarice ?
I don 't know . I didn 't have any food , any water , and it was very cold .
It was very cold .
I thought –
I thought if I could save just one , but ...
he was so heavy .
He was so heavy .
[ wind whistling ]
I didn 't get more than a few miles when the sheriff 's car picked me up .
Rancher was so angry , he sent me to live at the Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman .
I never saw the ranch again .
What became of your lamb , Clarice ?
They killed him .
You still wake up sometimes , don 't you ?
Wake up in the dark
and hear the screaming of the lambs .
Yes .
And you think if you saved poor Catherine , you could make them stop , don 't you ?
You think , if Catherine lives ,
you won 't wake up in the dark ever again ...
to that awful screaming of the lambs .
I don 't know . I don 't know .
Thank you , Clarice .
Thank you .
Tell me his name , Doctor .
[ Lecter inhales ]
[ door opens ]
[ clicks tongue ] Dr. Chilton , I presume ?
I think you know each other .
[ footsteps approaching ]
Okay .
- [ agent ] We found her . - Let 's go .
It 's your turn , Doctor .
- Out . - Tell me his name .
Sorry , ma 'am , I 've got orders . Have to put you on a plane .
[ Boyle ] Come on now .
Brave Clarice .
You will let me know when those lambs stop screaming , won 't you ?
Tell me his name , Doctor .
Clarice !
Your case file .
Hey .
Good-bye , Clarice .
[ Boyle , guard grunting , muttering ]
[ police radio chatter ]
[ classical piano ]
[ footsteps approaching ]
Ready when you are , Doc .
Just another minute , please .
Son of a bitch demanded a second dinner .
Lamb chops . Extra rare .
Wonder what he wants for breakfast . Some damn thing from the zoo ?
[ guard chuckles ]
[ classical piano continues ]
Good evening , gentlemen .
Okay , Doc . Grab some floor .
- Same drill as before , please . - Mm-hmm .
Ready when you are , Sergeant Pembry .
[ Pembry ] Okay .
- [ Boyle ] Hand me that , would you ? - Uh-huh .
Thanks .
[ Lecter ] Mind the drawings , please .
Thank you .
Jimmy , watch it ! He 's got me !
[ grunting ]
- [ snarling ] - [ screaming ]
Jesus Christ !
[ grunting ]
[ screaming ]
[ groans , sputters ]
[ Pembry ] I need help .
[ screaming ]
[ Boyle grunts ]
[ grunting ]
[ classical piano continues ]
[ Pembry groaning ]
Ready when you are , Sergeant Pembry .
[ people chattering ]
[ officer ] What is this shit ?
Did somebody go up on five ?
No . Nobody went up .
- Call Pembry . Ask him to tell – - [ gunshots ]
CP . Shots fired on five .
Repeat , shots fired on five .
Sergeant Tate !
[ man on radio ] Shots fired on five .
- [ Tate ] Holy shit ! - [ officer ] What the hell ?
- [ chattering ] - [ Tate ] Shut up !
Bobby , get the vest .
Right , Sarge .
- [ Tate ] Brady , Howard , cover the – - Look !
- [ elevator bell dings , faint ] - [ Jacobs ] It stopped .
Seal off a 10-block radius .
Get me the SWAT team and an ambulance , double quick .
We 're goin ' up .
[ police radio chatter ]
[ Tate ] Pembry !
Boyle ! [ echoing ]
[ hammers cocking ]
Oh , God !
Go .
- Clear . - Clear .
Command post , two officers down .
- [ Jacobs ] Clear . - [ officer ] Clear !
Lecter 's gone , Sarge .
[ Tate ] Prisoner is missing .
- Boyle 's gun is gone , Sergeant . - Repeat , Lecter 's missing and armed .
He 's stripped the bed .
Might be making a rope . Check all windows .
Where the fuck is my ambulance ?
- [ wheezing ] - He 's alive .
Sergeant Tate , he 's alive !
Get ahold of him where you can feel his hands , son . Talk to him .
What do I say ?
It 's Jim Pembry ! Now talk to him , damn it !
[ Tate ] Lecter 's missing and armed .
Pembry . Pembry , can you hear me ?
He took Boyle 's gun . Pembry got off one round . There 's a chance Lecter was hit .
Keep breathing in and out . That 's it .
You 're doing a good job . Oh , you look real good there .
- Yeah , you look ... real good . - [ sirens wailing ]
[ helicopters whirring ]
- You ready ? - Let 's go .
- Let 's do it . - Okay ? Let 's go .
- Got it ? - Yeah .
Lookin ' good , Pembry . You 're gonna make it .
You 're doin ' just fine . You 're doin ' all right . That 's right .
- Okay , I need that IV now ! - Lactated Ringer 's .
Can we get the strap ? Buzz , where 's the fuckin ' oxygen ?
Lookin ' good , buddy . That 's right . Stay with me . Stay with me here .
[ grunting ]
We 're losin ' him . Downstairs , quickly !
- And up ! - [ grunting continues ]
- Elevator ! Out of the way ! - [ Jacobs ] Clear the way !
[ officer ] Get out of the way .
- [ monitor beeping ] - [ man on radio ] CP to Tate .
Uh , roger , Lieutenant . Tate here .
I 'm on the elevator bringin ' Pembry down .
He seems to be hangin ' on .
Top three floors secured .
Main stairwell secured .
We think he 's on two .
[ lieutenant on radio ] Tate ? You still with me ?
Uh , we 're pretty sure he 's somewhere on two , sir .
That 's all for now . Over .
[ elevator bell dings ]
He 's on the roof of the elevator .
Okay , guys .
I see him . There 's a gun by his hand . He 's not moving .
- One warning . We need him alive . - Got it .
Lecter ?
Put your hands on your head .
One in the leg .
No movement .
Johnny , hold your fire . We 're coming into the car .
We 're opening the hatch .
Watch his hands .
If there 's any fire , it 'll come from us .
- Affirm ? - Got it .
[ siren blaring ]
Memphis General , this is Medical Unit 26 .
We 're inbound with a 50-year-old male police officer
with severe facial lacerations .
Weapon unknown . We 've got grand mal seizure activity , but he 's postictal now .
Copy .
Uh , vital signs are good . Pressure is 130 over 90 .
- Ninety ? - Yeah , that 's right , 90 . Pulse 84 .
We 've got him on lactated Ringer 's running ,
and , uh – and the , uh , patient is on 10 liters of oxygen .
Watch it !
[ Ardelia ] They found the ambulance in a parking garage at Memphis Airport .
Crew was dead .
He killed a tourist too .
Got his clothes , cash .
By now he could be anywhere .
He won 't come after me .
- Oh , really ? - He won 't .
I can 't explain it . He – He would consider that rude .
[ scoffs ] It 's over . She 's dead .
It 's not your fault it worked out like this .
Lecter said everything we need to catch him with is right here in these pages .
Dr. Lecter said a lot of things .
He 's here , Ardelia .
[ sniffs ]
Is this Lecter 's handwriting ?
" Clarice , doesn 't this random scattering of sites seem desperately random ?
Like the elaboration of a bad liar . Ta , Hannibal Lecter . "
" Desperately random . " What does he mean ?
Not random at all maybe . Like there 's some pattern here .
Yeah , but there is no pattern , or the computers would 've nailed it .
They were even found in random order .
Random because of the one girl .
The one he weighted down .
- Oh , Frederica Bimmel . - Right .
Yeah , from Belvedere , Ohio .
First girl taken . Third body found . Why ?
Well , she didn 't drift . He weighted her down .
What did Lecter say about the first principles ?
Simplicity .
What does this guy do ? He covets .
How do we first start to covet ?
We covet what we see –
Every day .
- Hot damn , Clarice . - He knew her .
- Mr . Bimmel ? - That 's me .
Hello . I 'm Clarice Starling . I 'm with the FBI .
[ door opens , closes ]
[ Clarice ] I sure appreciate you letting me take a look around , Mr. Bimmel .
I don 't know nothin ' new to tell ya .
Police been back here so many times already .
Frederica went into Chicago on the bus to see about a job .
She left the interview okay . She never come home .
Her bedroom 's how she left it . Upstairs .
Door to the left .
[ music plays ]
[ music slows ]
[ music continues ]
[ cat meowing ]
[ meowing continues ]
[ bird wings flapping ]
[ Clarice ] He 's making himself a woman suit , Mr. Crawford ,
out of real women !
And he can sew , this guy . He-He 's very skilled .
- He 's a tailor or a dressmaker or – - [ Crawford ] Starling –
That 's why they 're all big .
He has to keep them alive so he can starve them a while ,
so he can loosen their skin –
Starling , Starling , we know who he is and where he is . We 're on our way right now .
- Where ? - Calumet City , edge of Chicago .
- Be on the ground in 45 minutes with HRT . - Oh , that 's –
- That 's great news , sir , but how – - Johns Hopkins came up with some names .
We fed ' em into known offenders .
Subject 's name is Jame Gumb , aka John Grant .
Lecter 's description was accurate . He just lied about the name .
Listen to this .
Customs had some paper on him .
They stopped a carton two years ago at LAX :
live caterpillars from Suriname .
The addressee was a Jame Gumb .
Well , Chicago 's only 400 miles from here .
- I 'll be there in – - No , no , no , Starling .
There 's not enough time . We want him for murder , not kidnapping .
I need you to link him to the Bimmel girl before he 's indicted .
- See what you can dredge up in Belvedere . - Yes , sir . You bet .
- I 'll do my best . - Starling .
We wouldn 't have found him without you . Nobody 's gonna forget that .
Least of all me .
Thank you , sir .
- Thank you very much , Mr. Crawford . - [ static ]
Mr. Crawford ?
Thanks for the scraps , asshole . I got a better idea .
[ breathing heavily ]
Yeah .
[ stereo : rock ]
[ sighs ]
Okay , Precious , time for a little treat .
[ grunts ]
[ growling ]
[ stereo : man vocalizing ]
Precious .
[ whistles ]
- Come on , girl . - ♪ He told me ♪
- Come on , Precious . Come on , Precious . - ♪ I see you rise ♪
♪ But it always falls ♪
[ Catherine whistling ]
Come on , Precious .
- ♪ I see them come ♪ - I got a yummy , yummy snack for ya .
- ♪ I see them go ♪ - Come on . Come and get it .
♪ He said ♪
♪ " All things pass into the night " ♪
Precious !
Are you out there , you little shit ?
Come and get it , pretty girl .
♪ I must disagree , oh , no , sir ♪
♪ I must say – ♪
[ sobs ] Precious .
Please come . Come on .
♪ You told me ♪
♪ I 've seen it all before ♪
[ sobs ] Come on , Precious . [ sobs ]
[ weak whistle ]
♪ I 've seen my hopes and dreams A-lyin ' on the ground ♪
♪ I 've seen – ♪
[ sobs ] Precious , come on .
- [ growls ] - [ chuckles ]
Will you fuck me ?
[ Catherine ] Come on . Take that bone . Come on .
Come on . Come on . Come on . [ grunting ]
I 'd fuck me .
Come on .
- [ growling ] - [ grunts ]
[ yelps ]
[ gasps ]
I 'd fuck me hard .
I 'd fuck me so hard . [ chuckles ]
[ sobbing ]
No !
♪ Good-bye , horses ♪
- ♪ I 'm flying over you ♪ - [ humming ]
- [ sobbing ] - ♪ Good-bye , horses ♪
- ♪ I 'm lyin ' over you ♪ - [ barks ]
♪ Good-bye , horses ♪
- ♪ I 'm lyin ' , lyin ' , lyin ' ♪ - ♪ I 'm lyin ' , lyin ' , lyin ' over you ♪
[ singer vocalizing ]
[ siren wailing ]
Is that a good job , FBI agent ?
You get to travel around and stuff ? I mean , better places than this ?
[ chuckles ] Sometimes you do .
Freddie was so happy for me when I got this job at the bank .
Toaster giveaways and Barry Manilow on the speakers all day .
She thought it was such hot shit .
What did she know ? Big dummy .
Stacy , did Frederica ever mention a man named " Jamie " Gumb
or a Jame Gumb ?
- How about John Grant ? - No .
Would she have had a friend you didn 't know about ?
No way . If she had a guy , I 'd have known . Believe me . Sewing was her life .
- Did you two ever work together or – - Oh , sure .
Me and Pam Malavesi used to help her do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman .
Can you give me Mrs. Lippman 's address ? I need to talk to her .
[ insects clicking ]
So powerful . So beautiful .
[ Precious barking , whimpering ]
- Precious ? - [ whimpering continues ]
- Precious ? - [ Catherine ] Down here , you sack of shit !
[ barking ]
[ gasping ]
- Put her in that bucket . - No .
You get me a telephone and lower it down here , now !
Oh , poodlie-poo , Precious . Darling , are you all right ?
She 's in a lot of pain , mister . She needs a vet .
She broke her leg on the way down . I know it .
- She 's been licking it – - Hey , don 't you hurt my dog !
Don 't you make me hurt your dog !
You don 't know what pain is !
Get me a live telephone and lower it down here , and do it now !
- You fucking – Oh , fuck ! - You better be getting me that telephone !
[ shouts ]
I 'm gonna do it , mister !
I 'll cut her neck off , I swear to God !
[ stereo : rock blaring ]
- All right , mister , I 'm doing it ! - [ muttering ] Motherfucking –
[ ringing ]
- [ Catherine shouting ] I 'm in here ! Here ! - [ music blaring ]
- Okay , I 'm coming . - [ doorbell rings ]
We 're goin ' in .
Good afternoon . Um , sorry to bother you .
I 'm looking for Mrs. Lippman 's family .
- FBI ! Everybody down ! - FBI ! Down , now !
The Lippmans don 't live here anymore .
Excuse me , sir . I really need to speak with you .
- Clear ! - Clear !
[ stammers ] What 's the problem , Officer ?
Well , I 'm investigating the death of Frederica Bimmel .
There 's no one here , Jack .
Clarice .
Your name is ?
- Oh , uh , Jack Gordon . - Mr . Gordon . Good .
Um , well , Frederica used to work for Mrs. Lippman . Did you know her ?
No . Uh-uh .
Oh , wait . Was she a great big , fat person ?
Yeah , she was a big girl , sir .
Yeah , I – I may have see – No , I read about her in the newspaper .
Um , Mrs. Lippman had a son though .
Maybe he could help you . I got his card in here someplace .
- Do you wanna come in while I look for it ? - May I ?
- Yeah , sure . - Thank you .
[ Buffalo Bill ] Are you close to catching somebody , you think ?
Yes . We may be .
Did you ... take over this place after Mrs. Lippman died ? Is that right ?
Yeah . I bought this house , uh , two years ago .
Did she leave any records ? Any business records ?
Tax forms ? Um , list of employees ?
No , nothing like that at all .
Say , has the FBI learned something ?
The police around here don 't seem to have the first clue .
[ insect wings flapping ]
I mean , have you got like a description , fingerprints , anything like that ?
No .
Mm-hmm .
No , we don 't .
Ah .
Here 's that number .
Very good , Mr. Gordon . May I use your phone , please ?
[ snickers ]
[ chuckles ] Sure , you can use my phone .
Freeze !
Put your hands over your head and turn around !
Spread your legs !
Put your hands in the back , thumbs up –
Freeze !
[ panting ]
[ doorknob rattles , hinge creaks ]
[ rock song playing , faint ]
[ Precious barking in distance ]
[ Catherine ] Hey !
[ barking continues ]
[ Clarice panting ]
- [ gasps ] - [ song continues , lyrics indistinct ]
[ Catherine ] Hello ? Are you there ?
I 'm down here ! I 'm down here !
[ barking continues ]
[ grunts ]
Catherine Martin ?
Yes !
[ barking continues ]
FBI ! You 're safe !
Safe ? Shit . Get me outta here !
[ grunts ]
[ barking continues ]
[ song continues , echoing ]
You 're all right , Catherine . Now where is he ?
How the fuck should I know ? Just get me outta here !
Catherine , you gotta be quiet . Now shut that dog up !
Just get me outta here !
- [ Precious whimpering ] - Oh , God .
Catherine ,
I 'm gonna get you outta there , but right now you listen to me .
I 've gotta leave this room . I 'll be right back .
No , don 't you leave me here , you fuckin ' bitch ! No !
Don 't you leave me here ! This guy 's fuckin ' crazy !
[ Catherine ] Please !
I gotta get outta here !
Plea –
Catherine , the other officers will be here any minute now !
[ Catherine screams ] Wait !
- Don 't go ! Wait ! - [ Clarice ] Shh ! Quiet !
[ Catherine ] Come back . [ gasps ] Oh , God . Oh , God .
[ panting ]
[ grunts ]
[ Clarice panting ]
[ song continues , indistinct ]
[ Clarice grunts , pants ]
- [ clattering ] - [ gasps ]
[ refrigerator motor chugging ]
[ grunts ]
[ song continues , muffled ]
[ grunts , pants ]
[ Clarice gasps ]
[ rattling , switch clicks ]
[ high-pitched whine ]
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
[ hammer cocks ]
[ panting continues ]
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
[ loud clack ]
[ gasps ]
[ Buffalo Bill cries out , groans ]
[ gurgles ]
[ Clarice exhales sharply ]
[ grunts ]
[ panting ]
[ birds twittering ]
[ Clarice panting ]
[ police radio chatter ]
- [ Precious whines ] - [ Catherine ] No .
- You okay ? - Gunpowder . It 's nothing . I 'm okay .
[ reporter ] Agent Starling , how did you track Buffalo Bill to this address ?
[ applause ]
Clarice M. Starling .
- Congratulations . - Thank you .
Ernest W. Stevens .
[ applause ]
[ laughter , chattering ]
- Special Agent Starling . - Oh , Special Agent Mapp . [ laughs ]
- Phone call . - Oh , thank you . Excuse me , gentlemen .
Starling ?
Pilch . Would you take our picture ?
[ chuckles ] Sure .
Look , I just wanted to say congratulations .
[ Clarice exhales ]
And I 'm not much good at this kind of thing , so I 'm gonna duck outta here .
Okay . Sure . Um –
Thank you , Mr. Crawford .
Um –
Your father would 've been proud today .
Don 't forget your phone call .
Starling .
[ Lecter ] Well , Clarice .
Have the lambs stopped screaming ?
- Dr . Lecter . - Don 't bother with a trace .
I won 't be on long enough .
Where are you , Dr. Lecter ?
I have no plans to call on you , Clarice .
The world 's more interesting with you in it .
So you take care now to extend me the same courtesy .
You know I can 't make that promise .
I do wish we could chat longer , but ...
I 'm having an old friend for dinner .
Bye .
Dr. Lecter !
Dr. Lecter ?
Very important – Oh , excuse me . I 'm sorry .
- Is the security system all set up ? - Oh , yeah , the big-shot security .
Oh , thank you . I appreciate that .
[ man singing in French ]
[ singing in French continues ]